Preliminary Guide to the Graduate Council records, 1925-1967 RG0126
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Graduate Council records
1925-1967
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Graduate Council
RG0126
1.75 Linear Feet
The Graduate Council was created by University President Cloyd Heck Marvin. This collection contains minutes and summaries of the council.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
The Graduate Council was created by University President Cloyd Heck Marvin. The Graduate Council conferred only degrees of dissertations of philosophy. The faculty membership was composed of Masters in Research.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection contains minutes and summaries. The minutes are of the Graduate Council and run from 1931-55. There are five volumes of summaries of GW doctoral dissertations from 1925 to 1956.
Collection Organization
Organized into two series of records.
Washington (D.C.); Dissertations, Academic; George Washington University
- Records, 1925-1956; RG0126 Series 1; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains minutes of the Graduate Council from 1931 to 1955 and five volumes of summaries of GW doctoral dissertations dated 1925-56. The minutes includes the policy and charge of this university group.
  Formerly ACC#742
  - Minutes of the Graduate Council, 10/20/1931-02/21/1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Selections from the Minutes of the Graduate Council, 10/1931-05/1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Selections from the Minutes of the Graduate Council, 10/1931-12/1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Summaries of doctoral theses, 1925-1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    General note
    2 copies
  - Summaries of doctoral theses, 1939-1952 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Summaries of doctoral theses, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Records, 1930-1967; RG0126 Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains bulletins, announcements, brochures, and minutes. They range in date from 1930 to 1967. The materials concern research fields, chairs, history, doctoral programs, theses, dissertations, and selections from meeting minutes.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Graduate Council (1930-1967), 1930-01/1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Council (1930-1967) Bulletins, 1946-1964, 02/1946-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graduate Council (1930-1967) Doctoral Program, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Graduate Council (1930-1967) Meeting minutes, 1931-1955, 10/1931-12/1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Graduate Council Bulletin and The Source, 1963, 2006; Series 2 (Box SHARED 2, Folder 5)